DILLON DODGE

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

CONTACT

775.895.0837

✓ daustindodge@gmail.com

Reno, NV

in linkedin.com/in/dillonadodge

LANGUAGES

PHP

• C/C++

Java

Python

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- SQL Server & MySQL
- Linux & Windows
- Npm & Composer
- Laravel & React
- Git & GitHub/BitBucket

SOFT SKILLS

- Enthusiastic
- Team Player & Cooperative
- Dedicated & Motivated
- Problem Solving
- Quick to Learn
- Friendly & Personable
- Good Communication

INVOLVEMENT

- WNC Data Oversight Committee
- WNC Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion Committee
- WNC Search Committees

PROFILE

I'm a hard worker, a team player, self-motivated, and I enjoy working with diverse people. I have worked with Laravel, React and WordPress frameworks for web applications. I have also developed Restful APIs for Canvas LMS & OnBase ECM integrations using Lumen. I am confident in my knowledge and abilities to be an asset to any software/web development team.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Interdisciplinary Studies

• **Concentration in** Computer Science & Engineering University of Nevada, Reno

Associate of Arts

Western Nevada College

EXPERIENCE

Application Integration Developer

Western Nevada College | Feb 2022 - present

Responsibilities include developing and managing RESTful APIs with third-party vendors (such as Google accounts, Active Directory, PeopleSoft, Workday, etc) using Lumen, developing full-stack CRUD applications with REACT and Laravel, managing MySQL and SQL Server, managing versioning of our applications using Git and of our dependancies/packages using Composer and npm. I also assisted in a data warehouse migration, in which we moved from MySQL to SQL Server. Lastly, I am responsible for managing student workers' schedules and projects.

Junior Programmer Analyst

Western Nevada College | Nov 2019 - Feb 2022

 Responsibilities included working with a senior programmer, developing integrations and other projects using SFTP and working with the Webmaster on WordPress plugins. I also became familiarized with RHEL Linux, MySQL, some Apache, and PHP. I used PHP for both front-end and back-end web development.

LOA - IT Support

Western Nevada College | June 2016 - Nov 2019

 I started working at WNC in the Application Support & Development department. I supported the help desk, updated/created OnBase eForms, Workflows, and custom queries, wrote simple php scripts, and took inventory. I also set up and managed meetings with other departments during OnBase project development. I was also tasked with writing basic PHP logic for the college's website in conjunction with our Webmaster.